# KWAN, Kin Chung (KC)

Researcher - CG & HCI

A researcher from Hong Kong with PhD degree in Computer Science and with 6+ years of research experience in computer graphics (CG) and human-computer interaction (HCI). Published papers in top conferences and journal such as SIGGRAPH Asia, TVCG, and SIGCHI.

kckwan@ieee.org
Phone
+852-91887480
Address

Hong Kong, China

## **Research Interests**

Computer Graphics, Human-Computer Interaction, VR/AR, GPGPU, Computer Vision

## **Educations**

2009 – 2015	Ph.D. in Computer Sci. and Eng., The Chinese Univ. of Hong Kong, Hong Kong
2006 - 2009	B.Sc. in Computer Sci., The Chinese Univ. of Hong Kong, Hong Kong, Hong Kong

## **Academic Experiences**

2018 - present	Senior Research Assistant, School of Creative Media, City Univ. of Hong Kong, Hong Kong
2017 – 2018	Postdoctoral Research Fellow, School of Creative Media, City Univ. of Hong Kong, Hong Kong
2015 – 2017	Research Fellow, Caritas Institute of Higher Education, Hong Kong
2014 – 2015	Research Assistant, Caritas Institute of Higher Education, Hong Kong
2013 – 2014	Research Assistant, The Chinese Univ. of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

**Conference Helper:** PG2018

Reviewer: PG, CGI, GMP, TVCJ, ICSPCC, HIS, IMAD, ICSC, SIGGRAPHAsia Poster, UIST, Chinagraph, EG,

SIGCHI, CADCG, ISCMA

## **Publications (Selected)**

#### Published

- Mobi3DSketch: 3D Sketching in Mobile AR, (2019) K.C. Kwan and H. Fu. In Proceedings of the 2019 CHI
  Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI). ACM, 2019. p. 176.
- Pyramid of Arclength Descriptor for Generating Collage of Shapes, (2016) K.C. Kwan, C. Han, L.-T. Sinn,
   T.-T. Wong, and C.-W. Fu. ACM Transactions on Graphics (SIGGRAPH Asia 2016 issue), 35(6), 229.
- Packing Vertex Data into Hardware-Decompressible Textures, (2017) K.C. Kwan, X. Xu, L. Wan, T.-T. Wong, and W.-M. Pang, *IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics* 24.5: 1705-1716.
- Occlusion-robust bimanual gesture recognition by fusing multi-views, (2019) G. Poon, <u>K.C. Kwan</u>, W.-M. Pang. *Multimedia Tools and Applications: 1-20.*
- Real-time Multi-view Bimanual Gesture Recognition (2018) G. Poon, K.C. Kwan, W.-M. Pang, IEEE 3rd International Conference on Signal and Image Processing (ICSIP), pp. 19-23.
- A Two-Phase Space Resection Model for Accurate Topographic Reconstruction from Lunar Imagery with Pushbroom Scanners, (2016) X. Xu, H. Zhang, G. Han, <u>K.C. Kwan</u>, W.-M. Pang, J. Fang, and G. Zhao. Sensors, 16(4), 507.
- Towards using Tiny Multi-Sensors Unit for Child Care Reminders (2016) G. Poon, K.C. Kwan, W.-M. Pang, K.-S. Choi, *IEEE Second International Conference on Multimedia Big Data (BigMM). pp. 372-376.*

- Towards using Tiny Sensor with Heat Balancing Criteria for Child Care Reminders (2016) G. Poon, <u>K.C. Kwan</u>, W.-M. Pang, K.-S. Choi, *International Journal of Semantic Computing*, 10(03), 365-378.
- Where2Buy: A Location-Based Shopping App with Products-wise Searching (2017) K.C. Chan, T.L. Cheung, S.H. Lai, K.C. Kwan, H. Yue, W.-M. Pang. 2017 IEEE International Symposium on Multimedia (ISM) (pp. 438-443). IEEE.
- A Mobile Adviser of Healthy Eating by Reading Ingredient Labels, (2016) M.W. Wong, Q. Ye, Y.K. Chan, W.- M. Pang, K.C. Kwan, In Proceedings of the 6th EAI International Conference on Wireless Mobile Communication and Healthcare 2016.
- Locally Scale-Invariant Descriptor for 2D Whole-Shape and Partial-Shape Matching, (2015) K.C. Kwan,
   PhD Thesis, Department of Computer Science & Engineering, The Chinese University of Hong Kong.



Three-Dimensional Sketching in Mobile Augmented Reality. (2019) PWG Application PWG/PA/709/2/2019, approved to file in US.

• Unpublished • •

- [Title Hidden], H. Ye, K.C. Kwan (joint 1st author), W. Su, H. Fu. Under review in SIGCHI 2020.
- [Title Hidden], H. Ye, K.C. Kwan, H. Fu. Under review in SIGCHI 2020.
- Automatic Image Checkpoint Selection for Guider-Follower Pedestrian Navigation, K.C. Kwan, and H. Fu.
   In preparation for resubmission.
- Autocomplete Stylized Drawings from References, Y. Chen, K.C. Kwan, L.Y. Wei, H. Fu. In preparation.
- How to Wash Your Hand Properly? Bimanual Gesture Recognition for Hand Washing Training, G. Poon, K.C. Kwan, W.-M. Pang. *In preparation for resubmission.*

## **Skills**

C/C++	Swift	CUDA	\ Ja	va	Pytho	on	Matlab	HTML5	Javas	Script	Objective-C
OpenGL OpenCV		cv	GLSL	L OpenCL		Qt	iOS App Developn		nent	ARKit	

## **Teaching Experiences**

2009 – 2019 **Teaching Assistant.,** The Chinese Univ. of Hong Kong, Hong Kong

#### **Awards**

Japanese

Postgraduate Studentship (2009-2011) Excellent Teaching Assistantship (2010) Shaw College, Academic Merit (2009)

Languages

Cantonese
English
Mandarin

Personal Interests

Computing
Drawing
Playing Puzzle Game

Archery
Kendo
Piano